谨以此集，献给轴人浓子，感谢你的付出
摩登这个大家庭，永远印着你的名字
R.I.P.
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
翻译:  glida   洗七里    亲爱的小饭
翻译:  冰蓝    ET外星人    吃货丁小七
校对:  偷天换日赛太公 偷懒混日YY猫
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第一集
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
官方APP
更新下载手机搞定
讨论交流登陆升级
到各大市场搜索
"人人影视字幕组"
下载网址：app.zimuzu.tv
我们真的得走吗
Do we really have to leave?
是啊  我们不能再多待几天吗
Yeah, can't we just stay a couple more days?
我知道  我也很难受
I know -- it's killing me.
明天是阿波罗剧院的开麦之夜
Tomorrow's open-mic night at the Apollo.
我们还会再回来  我也喜欢这里
Look, we'll all come back. I love it here, too.
跟纽约人相比  我很放松
Compared to New Yorkers, I'm laid-back.
来抱抱
Now, come on.
上楼收拾行李  不然你们可能赶不上飞机
Get upstairs and pack, or else you might miss your flight.
在纽约度过美好的一周后
After a great week in New York,
我得去罗利参加卡罗来纳州橱柜大会
I had to get to Raleigh for the Carolina Closet Caucus.
菲尔和我一直都想
Phil and I have always wanted
一起开车周游全国
to drive across the country together,
所以我们想来个自驾游
so we thought we'd make a road trip of it.
-再见  孩子们  -再见
- Bye! Bye, guys! - Bye! Bye! Bye!
我们会想你们的
We'll miss you!
就这样决定了  我们再住一晚
Okay, here's the deal -- We're staying another night.
什么
What?
你听到爸妈说的话了  他们说不行
You heard mom and dad. They said no.
我们还是会在他们之前到家  他们不会知道
Well, we'll still get home before them. They'll never know.
拜托  安迪和我刚分手
Oh, come on. Andy and I just broke up.
我还没准备好回去面对生活
I'm not ready to go back and face life.
我们要怎么付房费啊
Come on, how would we even pay for the hotel?
我们可以用卢克的园游会赔偿金
We can use Luke's carnival settlement money.
不行  那是我赚的
No way! I earned that.
摔下游乐设施的是我
I'm the one who fell off that ride.
受罪的其实是我们
We were the ones who really suffered.
在你的头消肿之前  我们都不能开灯
We couldn't turn on lights or make loud noises
或者发出很大的声音
until your head got small again.
我们不能用那笔钱  那是给我上大学用的
We can't use that money. It's for college.
好啦  好啦  花了吧
Okay, okay, let's spend it.
瞧瞧  我们一直没去成的寿司餐厅
Oh, look -- that sushi restaurant we never made it to.
是啊  我们努力过了
Oh, yeah. We tried.
可是他们没有五人桌
They just never had a table for five.
但这一趟我们玩得很开心  对吧
We had a lot of fun, though, didn't we?
-是啊  -是啊
- Yes, we did. - Yeah.
可惜的就是
Never got to get on
没有乘坐到中央公园游园马车
one of those horse-drawn carriages through the park.
艾丽克斯过敏
Alex's allergies.
都不知道原来还能单对马车皮革过敏
Didn't know you could be allergic to carriage leather.
但这依然是一段很棒的家庭时光
Still, just so much good family time.
家庭时光
Family time.
你的想法跟我一样吗
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
你可以不去开会
You could blow off the convention.
我们可以待在这里  度过浪漫的几天
We could stay here for a romantic few days
但别告诉孩子们  因为我们刚逼他们回家了
but never tell the kids because we just made them go home?
没错
Yes!
这是你第一次答对这个问题
That is the first time you've ever answered that question right.
我不要今天死
Not today!
小卡  外面天气真好
Oh! Cam, it is so beautiful outside.
你得...
You got to --
好吧
Ohhhh...right.
我们决定去密苏里州度过夏天
We decided to spend the summer in Missouri.
但我们过来后发现小卡的奶奶躺在临终床上
But we arrived to find Cam's grandma on her deathbed.
从感恩节到现在完全没变
Right where we left her at Thanksgiving.
我希望你能多体谅
Hey, um, I wish you'd be a little more mindful
我的家庭情况
of my family situation.
抱歉  我没意识到祈祷
I'm sorry -- I didn't realize the vigil
转移到了公用区域
had drifted out to the common areas.
小卡  拜托
Cam, come on.
她都95岁了  靠设备维持生命
She's 95 years old and plugged into a wall.
也许是时候...
Maybe it's time to, you know...
什么  你什么意思  米奇尔
What? What are you saying, Mitchell?
我们该停了设备吗
That we should pull the plug?
愿上帝怜悯你
Lord o' mercy.
你有轮班去陪过奶奶吗
Have you even taken your turn sitting with Gram?
没有  她才不想要我陪  她恨我
No, she doesn't want me there. She hates me.
又来了
This again.
小卡  她称我为"那娘炮"
Cam, she refers to me as "the sissy."
你听错了
You heard that wrong.
因为她继承的假牙  我们很难听懂她的话
She's hard to understand because of the dentures she inherited.
你知道那假牙是儿童钢琴的琴键做的
You know they were made from the keys of a child's piano.
而且对昏迷的人能说什么啊
What do you even say to someone in a coma?
妈妈读着她的诗
Well, Mama's reading her poetry.
莉莉朗诵《圣经》
Lily's reciting scripture.
小帕和我打算唱我们小时候改编的歌
Pam and I are gonna sing a song we wrote when we were younger,
《甜蜜之家阿拉奶奶》
"Sweet Home Ala-gramma."
原曲是知名歌曲《甜蜜家乡阿拉巴马》
好  教我唱吧
Okay, yeah, t-teach me that.
抱歉  她是你的阿拉奶奶吗
Oh, I'm sorry -- Is she your Ala-gramma?
好吧  我会想想的
Oh, fine. I'll think of something.
* 前进... *
* Onward -- *
抱歉
Sorry.
这衣领好痒
This collar itches.
别挠了  你们看起来都很帅
Stop it. You all look so handsome.
我们看起来像是三剑客
We look like The Three Amigos.
我们在华雷斯
We were in Juarez
参加我19岁的可爱表妹玛丽索的第三次婚礼
for my sweet 19-year-old cousin Marisol's third wedding.
真是太美了
It was so beautiful.
谢天谢地他们按时挖通了地道
Thank God that they finished that tunnel in time
她爸爸才能及时偷渡赶到
for her father to make it.
杰  别玩手机了  你错过了一切
Ay, Jay, stop with the phone. You're missing everything.
等等  我在为本周末的父亲节
Hang on -- I'm trying to lock up some sausages
订一些香肠
for Father's Day this weekend.
要是等到最后才订
You wait till the last minute, you wind up eating
就只能跟嬉皮士一样  吃鸡肉苹果味香肠了
chicken and apple, like some damn hippie.
双击
Double click!
那妖妇  曼尼  跟我来跳舞
La Diabla. Manny, come dance with me.
我去  真他娘好吃
Son of a bitch, that's good!
你好  杰
Hola, Jay.
桑娅
Oh, hey...Sonia.
我看见歌洛莉亚躲着我了
I see Gloria's avoiding me.
她还在生气我转发给她了那封群发邮件
She's still mad because I forwarded her that mass e-mail.
也许吧  也可能是上次你们见面时
Could be that, or it could be the last time you saw her,
你想抢走我  再杀了她
you tried to steal me and kill her.
我姐姐怎么样
So, how is my sister?
很好啊  好极了
Fantastic. Great.
当然了  有了乔和她的辣酱生意
'Course, with Joe and also her hot-sauce business,
她可有得忙的
she got a lot on her plate.
你吃过这种墨西哥曲奇吗
Hey, have you tried one of these Mexican cookies?
我们称呼它为曲奇而已
They just call them cookies.
我一会儿要跟歌洛莉亚谈谈
I'll speak with Gloria later.
我得先把这个放到礼物桌上
I have to drop this at the gift table.
太好了
Great.
我的座位发冷  花儿也都枯萎了
My seat is cold, and the flowers wilted.
看来我妹妹来过这里了
I see that my sister has been here.
你能放下那仇了吗
Will you get over that?
她刚刚很友好  我们聊了聊乔
She couldn't have been nicer. We talked about Joe.
我告诉她你的辣酱生意做得有多好
I told her how well your hot-sauce business was going.
对了  你吃过这种曲奇了吗
By the way, have you tried one of these cookies?
你干嘛告诉她辣酱的事
Why did you tell her about the sauce?
各位  拿上你们的东西
Everybody, get your things.
我们得马上离开华雷斯
We have to leave Juarez right now!
什么  我花了45分钟才穿上这身衣服
What?! It took me 45 minutes to get into this outfit!
你知道桑娅会有多神经病
You know how crazy Sonia can be.
现在她知道了
She's gonna be so jealous now that she knows
我是个非常成功的女商人  她会非常嫉妒的
that I am a very successful businesswoman.
那生意你不是还亏了400刀吗
Aren't you 400 bucks in the hole on that thing?
你不觉得这样不好吗
You don't think this looks bad --
晚餐开始前就离开这里
us walking out before dinner?
乔发烧了  他...他在大出汗呢
Joe has a fever, and he -- he's sweating very much.
没有  我才没有
No, I'm not.
我要收回我说的话
I'm gonna reverse what I said.
中央公园租狗生意  能大赚特赚的点子
Central Park dog rentals -- million-dollar idea.
对啊  而且可能度假让我嗨到糊涂了
Yeah, and maybe it's just the high of being on vacation,
但是还有比美洲旅鸽[已灭绝]更高贵的鸟吗
but is there a bird more majestic than the American pigeon?
穿衣服  我们出去吃早餐披萨
Get dressed. We're going out for walk-around breakfast pizza.
糟糕  忘拿钥匙了
Oh! Shoot. Forgot my room key.
我得给我爸拍一张这种镶板的照片
Oh! I've got to get a picture of this paneling for my dad.
芳香型雪松木刨花板  完全改变这个行业
Aromatic cedar flakeboard -- game a-changed.
我爱死我的性感小衣柜狂了
I love my sexy little closet nerd.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
我去迅速泡个澡
I'm gonna take a quick tub.
我们得给孩子们打电话查查岗  假装"在路上"
We should check in with the kids from "the road."
对对对
Oh, right, right.
我们还得去帮酒搞点冰块来
We should also maybe get some ice for drinks.
我们去大堂等他吧  反正我得喝点咖啡
Let's wait for him in the lobby. I need coffee anyway.
隔壁房间的人做爱声大得我一晚上没睡
The people next door kept me up all night with their sex noises.
我听到了结尾部分
I caught the end of that.
那男的听着像个被吓到的鬼
He sounded like a scared ghost.
天啊  是老妈
Oh, my God. It's Mom.
保持冷静
Uh, well, stay calm.
就说我们在家  我们昨晚飞回来的
Uh, we're home, we flew in last night.
走吧  她肯定想跟卢克说话啊
Oh. Come on. She's gonna want to talk to Luke.
老妈
Hi, Mom.
亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
从西弗吉尼亚给你打电话哦
I'm coming to you from West Virginia.
你们俩今天要做什么呀
What are you girls doing today?
我和艾丽克斯刚出来逛街
Oh, you know, me and Alex just out shopping.
你在跟谁打电话
Who are you talking to?
老爸  你在跟谁打电话
Dad. Who are you talking to?
-老妈  -老妈
- Mom. - Mom.
-俩闺女  -卢克
- The girls. - Luke.
等下
Hold on.
我告诉她们我们在西弗吉尼亚
I told them we were in West Virginia.
-你说什么  -肯塔基
- What did you say? - Kentucky.
老妈以为我们在逛街
Mom thinks we're shopping.
我跟老爸说我在给我们做早餐
I told Dad I was making us breakfast.
你什么时候给我们做过早餐了
When have you ever made us breakfast?!
好吧  姑娘们  我得走了
Okay, girls, um, I got to go.
-我们也是  开车注意安全哦  -拜
- Us too. Drive safely. - Bye.
哥们  我得走了
Hey, buddy, I should get going.
有个警察过来了
There's a cop walking towards us.
可能是因为我们停在州界线上怪怪的
I guess it looks weird with us parked right here
我前座在肯塔基境内
on the state border with me up here in Kentucky
-你妈后座在西弗吉尼亚境内  -知道了
- and your mom in the back seat over in West Virginia. - Got it.
我得把早餐打包好
I should probably finish packing up the breakfast
送到她们正在逛的商场去了
I'm bringing to the girls at the shopping mall where they're shopping.
-好吧  再见  -再见
- Okay. See ya, pal. - See ya.
-就是这么简单  -搞定
- That's how you do that. - Done.
* 甜蜜之家  阿拉奶奶 *
* Sweet home Ala-gramma *
* 双眼与头发都是美丽的蓝 *
* Eyes and hair of gorgeous blue *
我一会儿再回来
I'm gonna come back.
别别别  你来得正好
No, no, no. I'm glad you're up here.
-我们一会儿再唱  -对对对
- We can finish later. - Yeah, yeah.
她喜欢你抚着她头发  揉她的脚
She likes it when you stroke her hair and rub her feet.
米奇尔  你要确保她舌头是湿润的
And, Mitchell, make sure her tongue stays moist.
我要怎么...
How would I -- Ugh.
奶奶好
Hey, Grams.
昏...昏迷感觉怎么样
How's -- How's the coma?
我的天啊  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
你想说什么吗
A-Are you trying to say something?
奶奶  很疼  放...放手
Grams. Ow, that hurts. Let -- let go.
奶奶  快放手
Grams, l-let go.
放手吧  奶奶  放手吧  奶奶
Let go, Grams. Let go, Grams!
你这是在跟她说什么鬼话
What the hell are you telling her?
怎么回事
What happened?!
我刚刚进来
I just walked in,
米奇尔在告诉她放手  她就真的"放手"了
and Mitchell was telling her to let go, and she did!
放手  我是说放手别抓我头发
Oh, let go -- let go of my hair.
打给马场的人  叫医生来
Somebody call the race track! Get the doctor!
-好多人来啊  -当然
Nice turnout. Sure is.
太奶奶在世看到这么多人在她土地会很生气
Grams would hate all these people on her property.
的确会
She sure would.
你好
Hi.
天啊  我觉得你的家人都虎视眈眈地瞪着我
Oh, my God. I can feel your family staring daggers at me.
真不敢相信他们觉得是我杀了奶奶
Can't believe they think I killed Grams.
说得好像我真的会叫她撒手人寰一样
Like I'd really be telling her to let go of life.
你把行李箱放进她房间
Well, you can see how they'd wonder
像准备要入住后  他们有这怀疑也正常
after you put your suitcase in her room.
你这么说是站在他们那边吗
It sounds like you're taking their side.
你不能怪他们质疑你所说的
You can't blame them for questioning your story
一名患关节炎并昏迷的女士揪你头发的故事
about a comatose arthritic woman pulling your hair.
这不是故事  这是真事
Not a story. A thing that happened.
-好吧  -好
- Fine. - Fine.
你把她爱看的电视剧
And you didn't help your case
意外洗掉了也更让人怀疑啊
by accidentally erasing her "Matlocks".
天啊  能"放下"了吗
Oh, my God! Just drop it!
不  不  我不是...
No, not -- not the... No. I -- I...
好吧  你们打算什么时候回来
Okay, so, when do you guys think you're gonna be back?
绝对会在父亲节到
Definitely by Father's Day.
好吧  我们想你们
Oh, okay. Well, we miss you guys.
不过也还剩三天呢
But at least it's still only three more days.
是不是有点太冒险
Was it a little risky?
只要出手的是专家就没问题
Not as long as the master did the talking.
我爱你们  再见
Aww. Love you both. Bye.
我们想你们
We miss you guys.
我得出去漆邮箱了
Got to run outside and paint the mailbox.
你只需要说句再见就好
All you had to do was say goodbye.
这下我们回家的时候还得漆邮箱
Now we have to paint the mailbox when we get home.
抱歉
Sorry.
我也是因为看到
It just popped into my head
自由女神像拿着油漆刷而情不自禁
when I saw the Statue of Liberty holding that paintbrush.
就是她为美国刷出自由的工具[是火把]
You know, what she used to paint freedom in America.
好吧
Yeah.
一个好谎的关键在于不节外生枝
The key to a good lie is keep it simple.
我一直夸它也没意义
Well, why don't I stop talking
不如直接给你带点尝尝吧
about how good it is here and just bring you some?
好吧  再见
Okay. Bye-bye.
我们得去买一块亚利桑那辣味羊奶酪
We need to pick up a wheel of Arizona spicy sheep cheese.
你就不能只说再见吗
Couldn't you just say goodbye?!
克莱尔  那上面写着"不要大声喧哗"
Claire, the sign says "No loud noises."
你会吓到魔术师大卫·布莱恩
You'll scare David Blaine.
所以  他就在果冻里坐了四天吗
So, he just sits in jello for four days?
我没懂这算哪门子魔术
I don't get how that's magic.
你不会懂的
You wouldn't.
我真希望爸爸也在这里
I wish Dad was here.
他肯定会超爱这个
He'd love this.
他不在  我们也不在这里
Well, he isn't, and neither are we.
还记得卢克以前把它叫成"果弄"吗
Remember how Luke used to call it "jeh-woh"?
真讨厌我不能跟他分享这一切
I hate that I can't share this with him.
魔术不是用来搞秘密与欺骗别人的
Magic isn't about secrets and tricking people.
菲尔  够了
Phil! Get it together.
跟你的男朋友大卫·布莱恩一样
Like your boyfriend, David Blaine,
我们得把这个秘密保守到死
we're taking how we did this to the grave.
我只是很遗憾他错过了这些
I just feel bad that he's missing out.
这是我跟他的专属爱好
This is our thing.
喂
Hey!
你永远不准告诉他这事
You will never tell him about this,
不然无照经营园游会没摔死的人  我们会亲手弄死
or we will finish what that unlicensed carnival started, okay?
我们打算飞回去过父亲节的那天早上
The morning we were set to fly back for Father's Day,
中西部地区的一场风暴导致航班取消
a storm in the midwest canceled our flight.
我们先去机场吧  肯定有航班的
Let's just get to the airport, and we will find a flight.
-出租车  -该死  被人抢了
- Taxi! - Damn it! It's already taken!
我好像买到了在丹佛转机的航班
Okay, so I think I got us on a flight through Denver.
你介意坐中间吗
Do you mind the middle seat?
能不摔就行啊
If it'll help.
不要什么事都扯上园游会的事好吗
This can't all be carnival-related.
出租车
Taxi!
杰  我本来打算来做香肠的
Ay, Jay, I was going to cook the sausage.
我不介意
Hey, I don't mind.
他决定接手应该是因为
He's taking over because we screwed up
我们搞砸了前几个父亲节
the last few Father's Days.
别说傻话  我来就行
Don't be silly. I got this.
我只要一想到前几个父亲节
When I think of the last few Father's Days,
就气得要炸
I quake with rage.
不介意的话可以多花点心思啊
Hey, maybe put a little thought into it.
比如不要叫披萨
Maybe we don't order the pizza.
真要叫的话
And if we do,
也许应该点够疯狂面包
maybe we get enough crazy bread for everybody.
抱歉  到底是谁把父亲节变成
I'm sorry, but who made Father's Day
常用于配披萨的黄油蒜香芝士面包
节日界里的讨人厌拖油瓶啊
the dirty stepchild of holidays?!
父亲节连首歌都没有
We don't even have a song.
-爸爸  -怎么了
- Daddy? - What?
我给你准备了礼物
Got you a present.
不愧是我儿子
That's my boy!
让我们看看  你这里面放了什么
Let's see. What do we got in here?
一个冰桶
Hey. An ice bucket.
我看到曼尼拿走酒店的洗发水
I saw Manny take shampoos from the hotel.
所以我也拿了些东西
So I took some things, too.
然后是一些大件
Then some bigger things.
我喜欢偷东西
I like stealing.
这会让我心跳加快
It makes my heart go fast.
冰桶里有什么呢
And what's in the ice bucket?
一个吹风筒  谢谢  亲爱的
A hair dryer. Thanks, buddy.
谁这么早就来了
Who's here so early?
桑娅  你来这里干嘛
Sonia, what are you doing here?
你离开华雷斯太快了  我都来不及说再见
You left Juarez so fast, I didn't get to say goodbye.
我们是姐妹  我们不应该争吵
We're sisters. We shouldn't fight.
我想你
I miss you.
知道了
Okay, got it.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
桑娅  抱歉  快进来
Sonia. I'm sorry. Come in.
不行  我不能进
No, I couldn't.
不  你千里迢迢跑来
No, you came from so far away.
快进来  坐一会儿
Come on in. Stay awhile.
谢谢  杰
Thank you, Jay.
墨西哥曲奇
The Mexican cookies.
没想到能再看见它们
I never thought I'd see those again.
让我来帮你吧
Let me help you with those.
-桑娅阿姨  -你好  曼尼
- Hey, Aunt Sonia. - Hola, Manny.
我有一些行李在车上  来帮我吧
I have some luggage in the car. Come help me.
-好  -去帮你阿姨吧  去吧
- Okay. - Help your aunt. Go ahead.
你为什么要让她进来
Why did you let her in?
你得跟她聊聊
You have to talk to her.
我真的觉得她是来道歉的
I really think she's here to apologize.
你不像我那么了解她
You don't know her like I do.
等一下
Ohh! Wait!
你在干什么
What are you doing?!
好极了  杰  现在她绑架了曼尼
Great, Jay. Now she kidnapped Manny.
你怎么那么冷静
Why are you so calm?
我们不是应该跟着他们或者叫警察吗
Shouldn't we follow them or call the police?
不  不过是绑架而已  在我家这很正常
No, it's just a kidnapping. It's normal in my family.
绑架电话来了
Ransom call.
妈妈  我真的很害怕
Mom, I'm really scare--
她要我用辣酱生意来交换曼尼
She wants my hot-sauce business in exchange for Manny.
太好了  那她就欠我们400美金了
Good! Then she owes us 400 bucks.
而且孩子还能回来了
We get the kid back.
没门
No deal.
我会处理的
I'll handle it.
我的姐姐  我来解决
My sister, my problem.
这是我的节日
My holiday!
孩子们刚停好车
Oh! That's the kids pulling up right now.
-表现正常一点  -我生来就很正常
- Just act normal. - I was born normal.
不对  他们说我出生时自带刘海
Not really. They said I came out with bangs.
现在我们只要口径一致就行了
Hey. Now all we have to do is stick the landing.
别行为怪异露出破绽
Don't blow it by acting weird.
-我很想你  -伙计
- Oh! I missed you! - Buddy!
自驾游怎么样
Oh, how was the drive?!
很不错
Oh, it was great.
-没错  -是吗
- Yeah. - Yeah?
我们本该很早就到的
We would have been here a lot earlier,
但是路上太堵了...
but there was a ton of traffic on...
美国路上
A-America.
我们去找外公怎么样
What do you say we go find Grandpa, huh?
-好呀  -去吧  一起去吧
- Yes. - Here we go. Let's go.
这周过得好吗
So, uh, good week?
我也一样
Same.
-天啊  他们在聊天  -是吗
- Oh, my God. They're talking. - Are they?
好了  你们俩话唠
All right, you chatterboxes.
我们开始派对吧
Let's get this party started, huh?
是啊  都快4点了
Yeah, it's almost 4:00.
1点
1:00.
做得真不错
That was great.
真的吗
Really?
假的  但你说谎就这样
No. But that's how you lie.
去洗把脸吧
Go splash some water on your face.
大家好
Hey, guys.
你怎么样
Hi! How are you?
小卡和莉莉在哪里
Hi. Where are Cam and Lily?
他们还在农场
Uh, they're still at the farm.
我被驱逐出场了
I got banished.
你好像有很多话要说
Sounds like you're ramping up to a story,
但我还有些事要处理  所以...
but I got some stuff going on, so...
好吧  回家"太好了"
Okay. Good to be home.
好吧  小卡的奶奶  那个叫我娘炮的人
Okay, so Cam's grandmother, the one who called me a sissy,
她死了
she died.
而我在她去世的那一刻跟她独处
And I -- I was alone with her when it happened,
然后全家人都以为是我推波助澜的
and the family thinks that I nudged it along.
-小卡的奶奶死了  -我的天啊
- Cam's grandma died? - Oh, my God.
你还是这样  只要一说到死亡
You still do that thing where you smile
你就会开始微笑
whenever you talk about death.
这只是一种应对机制  很快就会好
It's just a coping mechanism. It's gonna pass.
从我十岁  我们在后院
You've been doing it since I was 10 years old
埋我的仓鼠时  你就这么笑了
and we buried my hamster in the backyard.
他叫美髯公
His name was Whiskers.
你能正常一下吗
Can you be a human being for one second?
在他们全家都针对我的时候
So, Cam totally took his family's side
小卡完全站在他家人那一边
when they all turned against me.
那不过是习惯而已
Well, that's just a reflex.
你也总是站在你家人的这一边
You always take your family's side.
得了吧  什么时候的事
Oh, come on. Where is that written?
还记得你第一次带小卡回家
Remember when you first brought Cam home
然后我私下跟你说
and I privately said to you,
"你最好再考虑要不要换一个"
"You might want to move on from this one,"
然后爸说  "我还以为你喜欢纯爷们"呢
and Dad said, "I thought you liked men"?
然后当小卡以为
And then when Cam thought
他发现到我们不喜欢他时
he was picking up on us not liking him,
你就跟小卡说他疯了
you told Cam he was crazy.
我好像真是这么做了
I guess I did do that, huh?
天啊  你和爸可真毒啊
God, you and Dad are mean.
你个杀人凶手还有脸说了
Aww. Says the murderer.
歌洛莉亚  我们不能干坐在这  打给桑娅吧
Gloria, we can't sit around doing nothing. Call Sonia.
让她带着曼尼和曲奇到一个双方同意的地方
Tell her to bring Manny and the cookies to a neutral place,
然后我们来完成这笔交易
and we'll make the exchange.
为什么我要交易  我们拥有一切筹码
Why would I make an exchange? We have all the leverage.
她手上有你儿子
She has your son.
她能怎么  抚养曼尼吗
What is she gonna do? Raise Manny?
别担心  他会没事的
Don't worry. He's going to be fine.
肯定还有更好的方法
There's got to be a better way.
我父母一定会担心死的
My parents will be worried sick.
话说回来  她为什么想抢你的辣酱生意
Why does she want your sauce business, anyway?
或许她有理由认为
Well, maybe she has a reason to think
这生意理应有她的一杯羹
that it should be partly hers.
我已故的阿姨
My late aunt
将那份辣酱秘方传给了我们姐妹二人
gave that hot-sauce recipe to both of us.
不是只给了歌洛莉亚一个人
Not just Gloria.
当时桑娅根本不在意那份秘方
Sonia didn't care about the recipe.
她以前可懒了
She was very lazy.
我当时说  "也许我会去美国卖辣酱
I said, "Maybe I'll go to America and sell the sauce.
试着闯出自己的一片天地"
Try to make something of myself."
所以我很婉转地劝她放弃了
So I gently talked her out of it.
她说我的主意蠢爆了
She told me my idea was stupid --
就像我所有的主意一样蠢
just like all my ideas.
然后我改变了主意  实现了她的梦想
And then I changed my mind, and I did her dream.
她有什么可生气的
What is she so mad about?
我很抱歉把你牵扯进这场夙怨
I'm sorry to involve you in this feud.
没关系
It's okay.
其实我开始明白你这边的辛酸了
I'm actually starting to see your side of this.
谢谢你
Thank you.
只要这不是那种
As long as this isn't that thing
被绑架的人爱上绑匪的情况就好
where the person gets kidnapped and then --
为何我到今时今日才注意到你是如此美丽
Why am only now noticing how beautiful you are?
我的天
Ay, dios mio.
惊喜
Surprise!
父亲节快乐
Happy Father's Day!
等等  你们特意飞回来的吗
Wait -- you guys flew in?
是的  我希望咱们今天能一起过
Yeah, I just wanted us to all be together today.
尽管你做事不过脑又欠考虑
In spite of your thoughtlessness and insensitivity.
那两个词是一个意思  不过随便吧
Okay, those mean the same thing, but okay.
我只想让你知道
Look, I just want you to know
我明白你为什么选择站在你家人那边
I understand why you took your family's side.
还有我很抱歉让你处在两难的境地
And I am sorry I put you in that position.
谢谢你  米奇尔
Oh, I appreciate that, Mitchell.
节哀顺变
I'm so sorry for your loss.
我能把我们的礼物从车里拿出来吗
Can I get our gifts out of the car?
太奶奶在遗嘱里给我们都留了东西
Grams left us all something in her will --
连你都有
even you.
她居然给我留了东西
She left me something! Aww.
尽管你又固执又顽固
Even though you're stubborn and pigheaded.
你又用俩同义的...  算了
Okay, again -- Oh...
曼尼回来了
Manny's here.
我不得不把他送回来
I had to bring him back.
我快被他那双大圆眼瞪疯了
He was driving me crazy with his googly eyes.
与你的明眸相比我这不过是毫无生气的肉球
My eyes are but lifeless orbs compared to --
行了  去给我拿瓶啤酒
Yeah, go get me a beer.
你胆敢抢走我儿子
How dare you take my son.
你胆敢抢走我的商业模式
How dare you take my business model.
二位  家里还开着派对呢
Guys, we have a party going on.
咱移驾到这边来吵
Let's take it over here.
歌洛莉亚  你自己也承认过
Now, Gloria, you have admitted yourself
你有专从这姑娘那偷东西的黑历史
that you have a history of stealing things from this one here.
又来了
Oh, here we go.
桑娅多完美
Sonia's perfect,
而歌洛莉亚干啥啥不行
and Gloria can't do anything right!
你这话听起来像我父亲一样
You sound just like my father!
等等
Hold on.
你是说多年来这些争执
Are you saying that all this
都只是要争父亲宠爱的诡异竞争吗
is about some weird competition over your father?
这就是你毁我一生的原因吗
This is why you sabotage my whole life?
因为爸爸爱我多过你
Because Papa loved me more?
指向我的手指倒是让我爱不起来
Don't love that.
我的天  好像是这样
Oh, my God. I guess so.
真让我难以置信
I can't believe it.
你也会嫉妒我
You are jealous of me.
只在这一个方面嫉妒
Just in that one area.
但我不该因为爸爸专宠你就对你不好
But I shouldn't treat you badly because Papa choose you.
对一个小女孩来说肯定很难熬
It must have been hard for a little girl.
当你在如此年幼时失去那份宠爱
When you lose a love like that at such a young age,
你将用余生去寻找替代品
you spend the rest of your life trying to replace it.
别指了
Okay.
如果你想要辣酱生意
Listen, if you want the hot-sauce business,
尽管拿去  是你的了
take it -- it's yours.
不  有你的嫉妒我就心满意足了
No, no. Your jealousy is all I need.
我想把一件对我很珍贵的东西送给你
I want to give you something that is very precious to me.
可别是曼尼
Not Manny.
那是一件我老早以前就该给你的东西
It's something that I should have given you a long time ago
它会让你和爸爸的感情永远紧系在一起
that is gonna keep you close to Papa forever.
莉莉  我们说好一起拆奶奶的礼物
Oh! Lily, we were gonna open Grams' gifts together!
我等不及了  太奶奶给你留了一块表
I couldn't wait. Grams left you a watch.
信里说
Oh! The note says,
"这是你爷爷从一个
"Your grandpa tore it right off of
死德国佬的手腕上拽下来的"
a dead kraut's wrist."
太感人了
Oh, that's so sweet!
我的礼物是这些
And I got these.
"我所有旧唇膏你就好好用吧
"Enjoy all my old lipstick,
你个大娘炮"
you big sissy."
她为什么要叫我娘炮
Why did she call me a sissy?
我  她不是那意思
I -- She doesn't --
我们这就拆奶奶的礼物了吗
Oh! We're opening Grams' gifts, huh?
-这份肯定是给你的  -好
- This must be yours. - Okay.
我们  我们也不是非现在拆不可
Let -- You know, we can do this later.
你都把你的拆了
You opened yours.
好的
Okay.
"当小卡初次带你回家来时
"When Cam first brought you here,
我以为我永远不会有看你顺眼的一天
I thought I'd never get used to you.
我从小就被教育仇恨你这种人
I was raised to hate your kind.
但当我见到你让我孙子那么开心
But seeing how happy you make my grandson,
我也忍不住在乎起你来了"
I... couldn't help but come to care for you."
小卡  是我误会她了
Cam. I was wrong about her.
是啊  是你误会了
Yes. You were.
我们把信拿去收好吧
Now, let's put this someplace safe.
别  等等  还有呢还有呢
No, no, wait. There's more. There's more.
"除了你还有谁
"Who else but you
更适合继承我挚爱的东方扇子
should inherit my beloved Oriental fan?
我希望它不会让你太想家"
I hope it don't make you homesick."
她本来说要把扇子给我的
She said I was gonna get that fan.
她临终前脑子非常不灵光了
Well, you know, she did get very stupid near the end.
好了  拆礼物时间到此为止
Okay, well, gift time seems to be over.
小卡  这是给莉莉的礼物对吗
Okay, Cam. This is Lily's gift, isn't it?
不是
No.
原来你才是那个大娘炮
Oh! So you're the big sissy!
给你
Here.
她的口红
Her lipsticks!
我猜你又要多想了吧
Oh. I suppose you're gonna read into this, too.
这些香肠闻起来好香
Wow, those sausages smell fantastic!
你还好吗  老爸
You all right, Dad?
还行  我不介意说我几句话
Yeah, I guess I could say a few words.
很感谢你们在这个伟大节日向我表示敬意
I appreciate you guys honoring me on this great holiday.
但我不是在座唯一的父亲
But I'm not the only dad here.
你们三个生在那个家真是走运  对吗
You three lucked out a little bit in that department, right?
确实是
We sure did.
我此生最好的工作
Best job I ever had.
养大两个非同凡响的女儿
Raising two dynamite ladies
还有夫复何求的最好的哥们
and the...best buddy a guy could ever ask for.
这是什么
Oh, what is with this?
-今年没有疯狂面包吗  -对啊
- No crazy bread this year? - Yeah!
我们在纽约又待了五天
We stayed in New York for five more days.
我看到大卫·布莱恩在果冻里
And I saw David Blaine in jello,
我一直超想告诉你  但她们不让
and I've been dying to tell you, but they wouldn't let me!
你真是个废物
You're a disgrace.
天啊  你们妈妈和我
Oh, my God! Your mother and I --
非常愤怒  愤怒
Are furious! Furious!
你们一直待在纽约
You were in New York this whole time,
却什么都没告诉...
and you didn't say anything --
听着  我不知道这一团糟是怎么回事
Now, I don't know what can of worms this is,
但我知道这是我的节日
but I know this is my day,
我要你们都冷静下来
and I want you to calm down.
你口袋里有个手机吗
Is that a phone in your pocket?
这是我的手机
That's my phone.
我从昨天就在找这个手机了
I've been looking for this since yesterday.
我会偷东西了
I steal now.
菲尔  你给我发短信了吗
Phil, did you text me?
是的  克莱尔让我给你发一张
Oh, yeah, um, claire asked me to send you a picture
我们在纽约住的酒店里衣柜的照片
of the closet in our New York hotel.
老天  这是你赤身裸体吗
Oh, my God! Is this you naked?!
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
亲爱的  你能给我爸发张衣柜的照片吗
Honey, will you send my dad a picture of that closet
免得我忘了
before I forget?
天啊  不要
Oh! No.
你们在吵什...
Hey. What's all the --
好吧  不要  谢谢
O...kay. No, thanks.
我已经对一个亲戚有不清不白的想法了
I already have confusing feelings for one relative.
好吧  这事就到此为止
All...right. Can this just be done now?
你是怎么...
How did you even --
等等  照片背景在下雨
Wait a minute. It is raining in the background.
但我们一起在纽约时根本没下雨
But it didn't rain while we were all there.
纽约只有昨天才下了场雨
It only rained in New York yesterday.
天啊  你们留在纽约居然不带我们
Oh, my God! You stayed in New York without us!
我们说谎了
We're liars!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不  是我的错  是我一直撒谎
No, it's my fault. I -- I kept the lie going.
我们真的要忽略
Okay, are we really glossing over the fact
我也能察觉出猫腻这事吗
that I figured something out?
我来告诉你们还忽略了什么
I'll tell you what else we're glossing over --
你们在父亲节表现多糟糕
how bad you all are at Father's Day.
我一个儿子有偷盗癖
I've got one son who's a kleptomaniac,
另一个喜欢上自己的亲姨
the other who's in love with his own aunt --
即使照你的标准也太恶心人
creepy even by your standards --
还有一个女儿  让我被迫看了她
and a daughter who I was forced to see naked
像刚出生时赤裸的样子
as the day she was born.
来吧  小卡  来亲我这个娘炮
Come on, Cam. Kiss me like the sissy I am!
-来的真是时候  -天啊
- Right on cue. - Oh, God.
祝我自己父亲节快乐
Happy Father's Day to me.
再来个锦上添花  我刚发现
Icing on the cake -- I just found out
我的妻子有严重的恋父情结
my own wife has major daddy issues.
让我不禁想这才是她和我一起的真正原因
Makes me wonder if that's the whole reason she's with me.
老爸  别乱说
Dad, come on.
我们或许毁了你的节日  我承认
We may have ruined your day, yes,
但你现在只是在穿凿附会
but now you're just spiraling.
每一段感情都有各自的问题
I mean, every relationship has its issues,
但歌洛莉亚超级喜欢你
and Gloria adores you!
享受这胜利吧
Take the win.
你们真这么想吗
You think?
爸爸真的好英俊
Papa was so handsome.
-真的  -真的
- Yes! - Yes. Yes. Yes!
好啦
All right!
你们每人盘子里都有一根香肠
You each have a sausage on your plate
我是根据你们每人的性格气质挑选的
I selected based on your individual personality and temperament.
这是血肠吗  为什么我的是粉色
Is this blood sausage? Because mine's pink.
我的也是粉红色...
Oh, my mine's pink, t--
很好笑  老爸
Oh. Very funny, Dad.
咬一口面包
Now take a bite of bread,
抿一口水净化一下味蕾
a sip of water to cleanse the palate.
我的闻起来很辣
Mine smells spicy.
来举个手  谁听到我说"闻闻香肠"了
Show of hands. Who heard me say "Smell your sausage"?
盒子上说这些猪每天被按摩
The box said these pigs were massaged daily,
然后从背后被杀
then killed from behind to
免得让恐慌荷尔蒙污染了肉质
keep the panic hormone from tainting the meat.
它们从背后被杀
They were murdered from behind?
我要你们注意三件事
The three things I want you to pay attention to
香气  口感还有余味
are bouquet, texture, and finish.
你们可以开始了
You may begin.
能给我来点番茄酱吗
Can I have some ketchup?
别说了  散会吧
We are done here.